Summary

I am now at Bosch Research North America as a Research Scientist in Visual Analytics. I finished my PhD thesis in Hong Kong University of Science and Technology. My research focus is in information visualization and visual analytics. Most of my research projects involve a combination of data mining and interactive visualization techniques.

Work Experience

- 2015.08-now Research Scientist, Bosch Research and Technology Center North America, Palo Alto, CA.
 - Conduct research in visual analytics
 - 2015.01-08 PostDoctoral Fellow, Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Clear Water Bay, Hong Kong.
 - Conduct research in visual analytics of graph structured data.
 - o Mentor junior students on various visualization research projects.

Education

- 2009-14 Ph.D, Computer Science, Hong Kong University of Science and Technology.
 - Thesis: Visual Analysis of Heterogeneous and Dynamic Graphs

Supervisor: Prof. Huamin Qu

2005-09 B.S., Computer Science, Zhejiang University (Chu Kochen Honors College).

Awards and Scholarships

- 2016 Best Paper Honorable Mention Award, IEEE VisWeek (VAST, InfoVis, SciVis)
- 2014 Best Paper Award, International Symposium on Visual Information Communication and Interaction (VINCI)
- 2014 HKUST Overseas Research Award
- 2013 IEEE VisWeek (VAST, InfoVis, SciVis) Doctoral Colloquium Student Travel Grant
- 2010-14 HKUST Research/Teaching Assistant Studentship
- 2006-08 Zhejiang University Academic Scholarships (1st and 2nd Classes)
 - 2007 Mathematical Modeling Contest 1st Prize in Zhejiang Province
 - 2007 The 5th Mathematical Modeling Contest of Zhejiang University, 2nd Prize

Referred Journal Papers

- [J8] VisPubData.org: A Metadata Collection about IEEE Visualization (VIS) Publications. in IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics, to appear
 - Petra Isenberg, Florian Heimerl, Steffen Koch, Tobias Isenberg, **Panpan Xu**, Chad Stolper, Michael Sedlmair, Jian Chen, Torsten Möller, John Stasko
- [J7, C8] ViDX: Visual Diagnostics of Assembly Line Performance in Smart Factories. *in IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (VAST 16)*, Best Paper Honorable Mention Award, to appear
 - Panpan Xu, Honghui Mei, Liu Ren, and Wei Chen
 - [C7] Interactive Visual Co-cluster Analysis of Bipartite Graphs. in IEEE Pacific Visualization Symposium (Pacific Vis), 2016
 - Panpan Xu, Nan Cao, Huamin Qu, John Stasko
 - [J6] Visualization of Bipartite Relations between Graphs and Sets. in Journal of Visualization, 2014 Hong Zhou, Panpan Xu, Huamin Qu
 - [J5] MViewer: mobile phone spatiotemporal data viewer. in Frontiers of Computer Science, 2014 Jiansu Pu, Siyuan Liu, Panpan Xu, Huamin Qu, Lionel M. Ni

[J4, C5] Visual Analysis of Topic Competition on Social Media. in IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (VAST 13), 2013

Panpan Xu, Yingcai Wu, Enxun Wei, Tai-Quan Peng, Shixia Liu, Jonathan J.H. Zhu, Huamin Qu.

Developed a framework combining *text and time series analysis* techniques with *interactive visualization* to gain insight into the dynamics of the competition among different topics for the public's attention on *social media*.

[J3, C4] Visual Analysis of Set Relations in a Graph. in Computer Graphics Forum (EuroVis 13), 2013

Panpan Xu, Fan Du, Conglei Shi, Nan Cao, Hong Zhou, Huamin Qu.

Developed visualization techniques to analyze the homophily effect in a *social network*, and proposed a *set visualization* method employing the metaphor of railway maps.

[J2] Edge Bundling in Information Visualization. in Tsinghua Science and Technology, 2013

Hong Zhou, Panpan Xu, Xiaoru Yuan, Huamin Qu

Surveyed edge bundling techniques used for edge clutter reduction and linkage pattern enhancement in graph drawings and parallel coordinate plots.

[J1, C3] RankExplorer: Visualization of Ranking Changes in Large Time Series Data. in IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (InfoVis 12), 2012

Conglei Shi, Weiwei Cui, Shixia Liu, Panpan Xu, Wei Chen, Huamin Qu.

Visualized the ranking change among a large number of items such as search phrases, which are ranked by their popularity and constantly change over time.

Referred Conference Papers

[C6] Parallel Coordinates with Data Labels. in Proceedings of the 7th International Symposium on Visual Information Communication and Interaction (VINCI 14), Best Paper Award, 2014
[C6] Parallel Coordinates with Data Labels. in Proceedings of the 7th International Symposium on Visual Information Communication and Interaction (VINCI 14), Best Paper Award, 2014

Hong Zhou, Panpan~Xu, Zhong Ming, Huamin Qu

[C2] Visualization of Taxi Drivers' Income and Mobility Intelligence. in *International Symposium on Visual Computing*, 2012

Yuan Gao, Panpan Xu, Lu Lu, He Liu, Siyuan Liu, Huamin Qu

[C1] Visual analysis of people's mobility pattern from mobile phone data. in *International Symposium on Visual Information Communication and Interaction*, 2011

Jiansu Pu, Panpan Xu, Huamin Qu, Weiwei Cui, Siyuan Liu, Lionel M. Ni

Internship and Visiting Experiences

2014 Visiting Student, Information Interface Lab (IILab) at Georgia Institute of Technology Mentor: Prof. John Stasko

2012-13 Research Intern, Microsoft Research Asia

Mentor: Dr. Yingcai Wu

Professional Activities

Program Committee, IEEE Pacific Visualization Symposium (PacificVis) Papers 2017 Program Committee, IEEE Pacific Visualization Symposium (PacificVis) Notes 2016

ACM SIGCHI

Reviewer

- o IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics
- IEEE VIS (VAST and InfoVis)
- The EG/VGTC Conference on Visualization (EuroVis)
- IEEE Pacific Visualization Symposium (PacificVis)
- IEEE Computer Graphics and Applications Magazine

Doctoral Colloquium, IEEE VisWeek 2013

Misc Projects

2014 Citation Visualization VIS 25 Anniversary (with Information Interface Lab in Georgia Tech, displayed at IEEE VIS conference)

- o Responsible for the visual design and the implementation of the demo
- Visualization implemented with D3.js, underscore.js, and networkx graph library in Python
- Live at http://www.cc.gatech.edu/gvu/ii/citevis/VIS25/
- 2013 Visual Analysis of Mobile Checkin Data (with Huawei Noah's Ark Lab).
 - o Responsible for the overall design of the system
 - Large scale spatial-temporal data visualization
 - User behaviour analysis
 - Visualization implemented with Java, Prefuse visualization library and OpenStreetMap API

Technical Skills

Languages Java, JavaScript, Python, C/C++, R, C#

Vis Toolkits D3.js, Prefuse

Graphics WebGL, OpenGL, Shader Language (GLSL), CUDA (earlier versions)

Others Version Control Systems (Git), Web Development (html, css, javascript), Front-end framework (React.js), Databases (MySQL, SQLite), Graphic Design Softwares (Adobe Illustrator), Visualization softwares (Tableau, Spotfire), etc.

Teaching Experience

2010-2013 Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Teaching Assistant

2011, 2013 Computer Graphics, Teaching Assistant

2010 Object-Oriented Programming and Data Structures, Teaching Assistant

The tasks of teaching assistant include leading tutorial and lab sessions of the course, designing exam questions, and grading homeworks.